The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation, or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: Thanks for coming.
教授：谢谢您的光临。
I know there's a problem set due.
我知道有一个问题要解决。
There's a quiz coming up on Thursday.
星期四有一个测验。
We won't have lecture on Thursday.
我们星期四不上课。
But we will have a quiz in the evening.
但是晚上我们会进行测验。
And there will be a recitation section tomorrow,
明天将有一个朗诵课，
which will be a quiz review.
这将是一个测验评论。
So, today's lecture is the last of the lectures in the shortest
所以，今天的讲座是最短的讲座的最后
path module.
路径模块。
And, unlike previous lectures, we're
而且，与之前的讲座不同，我们
going to be talking about optimizations that don't change
将要谈论的是不变的优化
the worst case, or asymptotic, complexity.
最坏的情况，即渐近复杂性。
But improve empirical, real life performance.
但是要提高经验，现实生活的表现。
Or potentially, and we can't prove this, but performance
或潜在地，我们无法证明这一点，但是性能
in the average case.
在一般情况下。
And so we look at a couple of examples.
因此，我们来看几个示例。
The first one you've already done.
您已经完成的第一个。
You can optimize Dijkstra when you're
您可以在需要时优化Dijkstra
looking for a single target.
寻找一个目标。
So, implicitly, we've assumed that we're
因此，隐式地，我们假设我们
solving the single source, any or all destination problem,
解决单一来源，任何或所有目的地问题，
when we've looked at the original Dijkstra
当我们看原始的Dijkstra时
algorithm, and the Bellman-Ford algorithm.
算法和Bellman-Ford算法。
Many a time, you're going to have a source, s.
很多时候，您将拥有一个来源。
And you want to find the shortest path
而您想找到最短的路径
to a specific destination, t.
到特定的目的地，t。
And you're doing this in your problem set.
您正在问题集中进行此操作。
And you can do some optimization.
您可以进行一些优化。
It doesn't change the worst case complexity.
它不会改变最坏情况下的复杂性。
But it reduces runtime.
但是它减少了运行时间。
And then you have a specific target.
然后您有一个特定的目标。
Especially if the target is close to you.
特别是如果目标离您很近。
And you don't have to traverse the entire graph.
而且您不必遍历整个图形。
Obviously, the algorithm has to prove
显然，该算法必须证明
that the particular path that was chosen
选择的特定路径
is, in fact, the shortest path from s to t.
实际上是从s到t的最短路径。
But it's a fairly straightforward modification.
但这是一个相当简单的修改。
And I will go over it, but you're actually
我会仔细研究，但实际上
implementing it in PS 6.
在PS 6中实施。
We talked about bi-directional search.
我们讨论了双向搜索。
Again, something you're doing from a standpoint
同样，从立场上讲，您正在做的事情
of breadth-first search.
广度优先搜索。
How can you get from one source to a destination,
您如何从一个来源到达目的地，
by doing bi-directional Dijkstra?
通过做双向Dijkstra？
And you can think of this as a frontier off shortest paths
您可以将其视为最短路径的前沿
is being constructed from the source, s, forward.
正在从源s向前构建。
And this backward frontier, you're falling edges backward,
而在这个向后的边界，您正在向后退边，
is being constructed from the destination.
正在从目的地构建。
And, effectively, when these two frontiers meet,
而且，有效地，当这两个领域相遇时，
you're going to be able to discover shortest paths.
您将能够发现最短的路径。
And, it turns out, it's not as simple as what I just
而且事实证明，这不像我刚才那么简单
described.
描述。
And so we'll have to look at that a little more carefully.
因此，我们将不得不更加仔细地研究它。
So that is our single source, single target problem.
这就是我们的单一来源，单一目标问题。
We won't cover this in 006.
我们不会在006中介绍。
But there's also this notion of all pairs shortest paths, which
但也有所有对最短路径的概念，
is something that 6046 covers.
是6046涵盖的内容。
And that is something that says, well, I
那就是说，嗯，我
don't know what the source is.
不知道来源是什么。
I don't know what the destination is.
我不知道目的地是什么。
For any pair of vertices, find me the shortest path
对于任何一对顶点，找到我的最短路径
from s to t, given that pair.
给定那对，从s到t
And so that, of course, is more work
因此，这当然是更多的工作
than even the single source, all destination problem
甚至比单一来源，所有目的地问题
because you're varying the source.
因为您在改变来源。
All right?
好吧？
So those are the three different shortest path problems.
因此，这是三个不同的最短路径问题。
And we've looked at that.
我们已经看过了。
And we're going to look at this today.
我们今天要看一下。
And we looked at it in the problem set.
我们在问题集中对其进行了研究。
But we'll spend time, specifically on this one.
但是我们会花时间，特别是在这上面。
And try and see if we can do some coding optimizations,
并尝试看看我们是否可以进行一些编码优化，
if you will, to improve run time.
如果可以的话，可以缩短运行时间。
All right?
好吧？
So, I emphasize that worst case complexity
因此，我强调最坏情况下的复杂性
is unchanged for all of the Dijkstra versions
对于所有Dijkstra版本均未更改
that we'll be looking at today.
我们今天要看的。
So I want to put up a pseudocode that you've written code
所以我想写一个你写过的伪代码
for at this point, which is the Dijkstra pseudocode.
此时，这是Dijkstra伪代码。
Because we'll take a look at it, and modify it, and execute it.
因为我们将对其进行查看，修改和执行。
So you have your set of vertices that you
因此，您拥有一组顶点
don't know the shortest paths to.
不知道到达的最短路径。
So we do have initialize is going to set d of s to be 0.
所以我们确实有将s的d设置为0的初始化。
And b of u, not equal to s, to be infinity.
u的b不等于s为无穷大。
And we have this set, Q, that we're
我们有这个问题Q
going to process and continually extract the minimum priority
进行处理并不断提取最低优先级
from Q. And, once we do that, we actually
来自Q。一旦完成，我们实际上
know the shortest path to you already.
已经知道通往您的最短路径。
That's what the Dijkstra invariant is.
这就是Dijkstra不变式。
And the process of extracting u implies
提取u的过程意味着
that we have to do a relaxation step that
我们必须放松一下
updates the priorities.
更新优先级。
And also modifies the parent pointers.
并且还修改了父指针。
So there's also the pi of v that is set to u.
因此，还有v的pi设置为u。
As well as d of v getting decremented.
以及v的d递减。
OK?
好？
So that's the Dijkstra algorithm.
这就是Dijkstra算法。
And one of the things that we can do,
我们可以做的一件事，
the straightforward thing, which is one line of code literally,
直截了当的事情，从字面上看是一行代码，
is to say that, if you know what the single target is, then
就是说，如果您知道单个目标是什么，那么
you simply stop if u equals t.
您只要u等于t就停止。
So no need to stop when Q becomes null.
因此，当Q变为空时，无需停止。
Or, you don't get to the point where Q is null.
否则，您将无法达到Q为零的地步。
You stop when you've lifted off the y vertex from Q. All right?
从Q离开y顶点时，您会停下来。好吗？
And so, obviously, this will run faster,
因此，显然，这将运行得更快，
assuming this check is a 0 time check.
假设此检查是0次检查。
And that's really one instruction,
那真的是一条指令，
so you can think of it that way.
所以你可以这样想。
And you will, basically, run faster for sure,
基本上，您可以肯定会更快地运行，
when you have a specific target.
当您有特定目标时。
It may be the case that your target is the last vertex
您的目标可能是最后一个顶点
that you find.
你发现的。
And in that case, you run no slower.
在这种情况下，您的运行速度不会变慢。
All right?
好吧？
So that's something that you looked at.
这就是您所看的东西。
And that takes care of the first optimization corresponding
并负责相应的第一个优化
to single source, single target.
单一来源，单一目标。
Let's talk about something that's
让我们谈谈
a little more interesting, and non-obvious,
更加有趣，而且不明显，
which is the notion of bi-directional search.
这是双向搜索的概念。
And, in bi-directional search, we have s.
并且，在双向搜索中，我们有。
And we have t.
我们有。
And we have a bunch of nodes in between,
我们之间有一堆节点，
corresponding to this graph here.
与此图相对应。
And what you do is, you alternate search
而您要做的是，您交替搜索
in the forward direction and backward direction.
在前进方向和后退方向。
So, you're going to do one step of Dijkstra, standard Dijkstra
因此，您将要执行Dijkstra（标准Dijkstra）的一个步骤
that starts with s.
以s开头。
And goes forward.
并前进。
And so, you could imagine that you're forward
因此，您可以想象自己正在前进
search in the first step, you're going to pick the vertex, s,
在第一步中进行搜索，您将选择顶点s，
off of Q. And you're going to process
Q。然后您将要处理
the edges that come out of s.
s产生的边缘。
And that would correspond with these two edges.
那将与这两个边缘相对应。
And so that's one step of forward search, going forward.
因此，这是向前搜索，向前迈出的一步。
And then you stop with the forward search,
然后停止前进搜索，
and you do a step of backward search.
然后您进行了向后搜索。
And so, you go backward search, and I'll
因此，您进行向后搜索，我会
explain exactly what this means, backward search from t.
从t向后搜索，确切解释这意味着什么。
And the important thing is that you're
重要的是你
following edges backward.
跟随边缘向后。
So that means your data structure
因此，这意味着您的数据结构
has to, essentially, have these edges that can be traversed
本质上必须具有这些可以遍历的边缘
in either the forward direction, or the reverse direction.
正向或反向。
So that's something to keep in mind.
所以这是要牢记的。
But what will happen here is simply
但是这里会发生的只是
that your first frontier of backward search,
您的反向搜索的第一个领域，
t now, in the backward search, is the minimum priority.
现在，在向后搜索中，t是最小优先级。
So , we're going to have to have two priorities corresponding
因此，我们将必须有两个优先级对应
to s in the fourth search, where that's a straightforward one.
到第四搜索中，这很简单。
v of s equals 0.
s的v等于0。
And we should think of it as d of f s equals 0.
我们应该将其视为fs的d等于0。
And we have d of b t equals 0.
并且bt的d等于0。
And these subscripts correspond to these two
这些下标对应于这两个
different priorities.
不同的优先级。
And it's exactly complimentary.
而且完全是免费的。
Only the source, s, in the forward search,
在前向搜索中，只有源s
has 0 priority in the beginning.
开头的优先级为0。
Everything else has infinite priority.
其他所有事物都有无限的优先权。
Only the target, or destination, has
只有目标或目的地具有
0 priority in the backward search.
向后搜索优先级为0。
Everything else is infinity.
其他一切都是无限的。
And you go forward, backward, forward, backward.
然后您前进，后退，前进，后退。
And so on.
等等。
And the question is, when do you stop?
问题是，什么时候停止？
And we have to talk about that.
我们必须谈论这一点。
And, it turns out, it's not a perfectly straightforward
而且，事实证明，这并非完全简单
stopping condition.
停止条件。
But it's something that will make sense, hopefully,
但这是有意义的，希望，
when I get around to describing it.
当我开始描述它时。
But, having said all that, let's just
但是，说了这么多，让我们
put down all of the different data structures
放下所有不同的数据结构
that we have to have.
我们必须拥有的。
And it's kind of a doubling of the data structure,
这是数据结构的两倍，
right, because just like I double the priorities,
是的，因为就像我将优先级加倍一样，
I also need two different min priority
我还需要两个不同的最小优先级
queues, corresponding to Q f and Q b.
队列，对应于Q f和Q b。
And, as I said before, these edges
而且，正如我之前所说，这些优势
have to be traversable in the backward direction.
必须在反向方向上遍历。
So this edge, in the graph, goes this way.
因此，图中的这一边沿这种方式移动。
But you're going in the backward direction,
但是你在往后走，
as you are growing your backward frontier.
随着您不断发展落后领域。
OK?
好？
That's important to understand.
了解这一点很重要。
So let me put down all of the specifics associated
所以让我放下所有相关的细节
with these data structures.
这些数据结构。
df u correspond to the distances for the forward search.
df u对应于向前搜索的距离。
And db u correspond to the distances
和db u对应于距离
for the backward search.
用于向后搜索。
OK?
好？
And, of course, we're going to have
而且，当然，我们将拥有
to have priority queues, plural.
具有多个优先级队列。
Qf corresponding to the forward search.
Qf对应于正向搜索。
And Qb corresponding to the backward search.
与Qb相对应的向后搜索。
And in initialize, as I said before,
正如我之前所说，在初始化中
we're going to initialize df s to be 0 and db t equals 0.
我们将df初始化为0，而db t等于0。
And then everything, the df's and the db's, are
然后，df和db的所有内容
going to be infinity.
将无限。
All right?
好吧？
OK.
好。
Great.
大。
So that's what we have here.
这就是我们在这里所拥有的。
Now, first question.
现在，第一个问题。
Roughly speaking, as I said, you can imagine intuitively
粗略地说，正如我所说，您可以凭直觉想象
that you're going to terminate the search when
您将在以下情况下终止搜索
these frontiers meet, OK?
这些边疆相遇，好吗？
Clearly, you can't terminate it when
显然，您不能在以下情况下终止它
these frontiers look like this, OK.
这些边界看起来像这样，好的。
So that's the intuition.
这就是直觉。
And you see that for the [INAUDIBLE]
您会看到[听不清]
first, as well, in your problem set.
首先，在您的问题集中。
But in the context of Dijkstra, single source, single target,
但是在Dijkstra的背景下，单一来源，单一目标，
can someone tell me what the termination condition
有人可以告诉我终止条件是什么
should be by looking at the code?
应该通过看代码？
I want a more specific, or a more concrete,
我想要一个更具体或更具体的内容
termination condition that I can actually code up,
我可以实际编码的终止条件，
as opposed to saying, the frontiers meet.
而不是说，边疆汇合。
Which, you know, I don't know how to code.
您不知道该怎么编码。
OK?
好？
Someone else?
其他人？
All right, go for it.
好吧，去吧。
AUDIENCE: When there's some node that
听众：当有某个节点
can keep track of two different cost values from--
可以跟踪-
PROFESSOR: The Qf and the Qb, that's correct.
教授：Qf和Qb是正确的。
And, somehow--
而且，
AUDIENCE: Somehow they're cost runs
听众：不知何故它们是成本运行
to get there from the start and from the [INAUDIBLE].
从一开始就从[音频不清晰]到达那里。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
It's close.
关闭了。
It's not quite something I can code up.
我还不能编写代码。
Someone want to improve that?
有人想要改善吗？
I want something very, very specific.
我想要一些非常非常具体的东西。
Someone?
有人吗
Go for it.
去吧。
AUDIENCE: The node has been extracted from both Qf and Qb.
听众：该节点已从Qf和Qb中提取。
PROFESSOR: The node which has been
教授：该节点已
extracted from both Qf and Qb.
从Qf和Qb中提取。
So, the reason I didn't quite buy your answer
所以，我之所以不买你的答案
was, finite part is obviously correct.
过去，有限的部分显然是正确的。
But I wanted a specific condition
但是我想要一个特定的条件
that says, I'm going to do extract-min,
那就是说，我要提取分钟
just like I said when I extract-min and u equals t,
就像我说的那样，当我提取min且u等于t时，
I stop with the single source, single target.
我从单一来源，单一目标开始。
In the bi-directional case, I need
在双向情况下，我需要
to pull out a node from Qf.
从Qf中拉出一个节点。
And pull out a node from Qb.
并从Qb中拉出一个节点。
And then I get to stop, all right?
然后我停下来，好吗？
So, you get a cushion.
因此，您得到了缓冲。
You don't need to feel too bad because I
你不必因为我感到难过
think you already have a cushion.
以为你已经坐垫了。
Yeah.
是的
I know that.
我知道。
I know everyone who has cushions.
我知道每个有垫子的人。
Right.
对。
Actually, I don't.
其实我不知道
But I'm going to pretend I do.
但是我要假装我这样做。
So, the termination condition is that some vertex, and this is
因此，终止条件是某个顶点，这是
correct, some vertex, u, has been processed,
正确，某些顶点u已被处理，
both in the forward search and the backward search.
在向前搜索和向后搜索中都可以。
OK?
好？
That corresponds to the frontiers meeting.
那相当于边疆会议。
But, specifically, it's been deleted,
但是，具体地说，它已被删除，
or extracted from both Qf and Qb.
或从Qf和Qb中提取。
So that's actually the easier question.
所以这实际上是一个更简单的问题。
Visit a harder question, which is how do we find the shortest
访问一个更棘手的问题，那就是我们如何找到最短的问题
path after termination from s to t?
从s到t终止后的路径？
OK?
好？
And I should say specifically, that-- and I forgot
我应该特别说-我忘记了
to put this up, which I should-- that we're
提出这个，我应该-我们
going to have to have pi f and pi b, which
必须要有pi f和pi b
this is the normal data structure.
这是正常的数据结构。
And the pi b is following the edges backward.
pi b跟随边缘向后。
So, in some sense, the predecessor,
因此，从某种意义上说，前任
in the case of pi b, what you're saying is, on this node
对于pi b，您要说的是在此节点上
here-- which I'll call v2 for example--
在这里-我将其称为v2-
is, if I'm going to choose this path here--
是的，如果我要在这里选择此路径，
and I need to obviously choose this edge here in any shortest
很明显，我需要在最短的时间内选择此优势
path that gets to t, right?
到达t的路径，对不对？
Because that's the only edge that goes to t.
因为那是t的唯一优势。
And so, what I'm saying here is that a predecessor of pi b t
因此，我在这里所说的是pi bt的前身
equals v2.
等于v2。
OK?
好？
That make sense?
有道理？
And then over here, if this was v1,
然后在这里，如果这是v1，
then I would have pi f v1 equals s.
则pi f v1等于s。
Right?
对？
That make sense?
有道理？
Everybody buy that?
大家都买吗？
All right, so how do I find the shortest path from s to t,
好吧，如何找到从s到t的最短路径，
after these frontiers have met, and I've terminated the search?
在这些边疆相遇之后，我已经终止了搜索？
How do I do that?
我怎么做？
Someone?
有人吗
Go ahead.
前进。
AUDIENCE: Well, given that data structure, you start at your t.
听众：嗯，考虑到数据结构，您从t开始。
And you keep on going back to the [INAUDIBLE]
然后您继续返回[音频不清晰]
until you get to the point where they've peaked.
直到达到峰值为止。
Then you use the pi f to go from that node,
然后您使用pi f从该节点开始，
all the way back to s.
一直回到s。
PROFESSOR: So, what I'm going to have to do
教授：所以，我要做的是
is-- but where do I switch, is the question.
是-但我要切换到哪里？
Where do I switch from pi f to pi b?
从pi f切换到pi b的地方？
There has to be some point where I switch from-- Yeah, go ahead.
我必须要从某个角度出发-是的，继续。
AUDIENCE: At the meeting point of the node
听众：在节点的交汇点
that was [INAUDIBLE] Q [INAUDIBLE].
那是[听不清] Q [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: All right.
教授：好的。
Is that what you were saying, too?
那也是你的意思吗？
OK.
好。
So the claim is, if w was processed first, extracted
所以说，如果先处理w，就提取
from both Qf and Qb, then find the shortest path using pi
从Qf和Qb中，然后使用pi找到最短路径
f from s to w.
f从s到w。
Right?
对？
So, you can use pi f to get from s to w.
因此，您可以使用pi f从s到w。
And the way you do that is by applying pi f to w.
这样做的方法是将pi f应用于w。
And then keep applying it until you get to s, OK?
然后继续应用它，直到到达s，好吗？
This is normal search, right?
这是正常搜索，对不对？
Everybody knows this.
大家都知道这一点。
You coded it.
您已编码。
So I hope you know it.
所以我希望你知道。
And then, we go find shortest path using pi b, right?
然后，我们使用pi b找到最短路径，对吗？
And you're going to constantly apply
而且您将不断申请
pi b-- and this is the backward path-- from t to w.
pi b-这是从t到w的后退路径。
And this follows the edges backward, all right?
然后沿着边缘向后走，好吗？
This sounds pretty good?
听起来不错吗？
Everybody agree with this?
每个人都同意吗？
Anybody disagree?
有人不同意吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: Pi b.
听众：Pi b。
If [INAUDIBLE], pi b would be like pi b b2 equals t,
如果[音频不清晰]，pi b就像pi b b2等于t，
because b2 [INAUDIBLE]--
因为b2 [听不清]-
PROFESSOR: That's a good question.
教授：这是一个很好的问题。
I might have done this wrong.
我可能做错了。
So, in the backward search, this can get pretty confusing.
因此，在向后搜索中，这可能会造成混乱。
So what do I have here?
那我这里有什么？
I want to follow the predecessor.
我想效仿前任。
You're exactly right.
你说的没错
Thank you.
谢谢。
Thank you for pointing that out.
感谢您指出这一点。
All right, so what I have here is
好吧，我在这里的是
when I look at this path that goes this way, all right?
当我看着这条路，好吗？
I'm going to look at the path that goes this way.
我将研究这种方式。
s is the predecessor of v1.
s是v1的前身。
v1 is a predecessor of, let's call this v3.
v1是它的前身，我们称其为v3。
v3 is a predecessor of v4.
v3是v4的前身。
I'm just talking about the regular forward path.
我只是在谈论常规的前进路线。
We have s to v1.
我们有到v1。
v1 to v3.
v1到v3。
v3 to v4.
v3到v4。
All the way to t, right?
一直到t，对不对？
So what I have here is correct.
所以我在这里是正确的。
The predecessor of v1 is s.
v1的前身是s。
The predecessor of v3 would be v1.
v3的前身是v1。
So I could write, pi f v3 equals v1.
所以我可以写，pi f v3等于v1。
Et cetera.
等等。
Now, let's just forget about the forward path, and let's
现在，让我们忘掉前进的道路，让我们
just talk about the backward path.
只是谈论落后的道路。
In the backwoods path, I want to be
在偏僻的道路上，我想成为
able to construct this backward path.
能够构建此后退路径。
It's got to be the reverse of what I have, OK?
这一定与我所拥有的相反，好吗？
And, in that case, what I'm saying
而且，在这种情况下，我的意思是
is that I want to move in this direction.
是我想朝这个方向前进。
So pretend that I've made the edges flip, OK?
假装我使边缘翻转了，好吗？
So, in that case, if I pretend that this edge is like that,
因此，在那种情况下，如果我假装这种优势就是这样，
and then I just apply the regular predecessor
然后我只是申请常规的前任
relationship, then t is the predecessor of v2.
关系，则t是v2的前身。
And that's the point you're making.
这就是您要提出的重点。
OK? t is the predecessor of v2.
好？ t是v2的前身。
And so, my apologies.
因此，我很抱歉。
I have pi b v2 equals t.
我pi b v2等于t。
And, if I follow this edge here, then I'd
而且，如果我在这方面保持优势，那么我会
have the appropriate relationship.
有适当的关系。
But let's just stick to this one because that's
但是让我们坚持下去，因为那是
the simple example.
简单的例子。
I don't quite know whether this edge
我不太清楚这个优势
is going to be part of my shortest path or not.
是否会成为我最短路径的一部分。
It might be.
有可能。
And that's something that we'll compute.
这就是我们要计算的东西。
But what I have here is the predecessor relationship
但是我这里是前辈关系
corresponding to the backward edge.
对应于后边缘。
And so, that's like flipping this edge.
因此，这就像翻转此边缘。
And, hopefully, that makes sense now.
而且，希望这现在有意义。
Thanks for pointing that out.
感谢您指出了这一点。
And so, let's talk about what happens here.
因此，让我们谈谈这里发生的事情。
We know what happens in the forward search.
我们知道在正向搜索中会发生什么。
You've done that before.
您之前已经做过。
In the backward search, what happens
在向后搜索中，会发生什么
is that I need to start-- according to this condition--
是我需要根据这种情况开始-
just like in the forward search, I found a w.
就像在向前搜索中一样，我找到了w。
And I continually applied pi of f to w.
而且我不断将f的pi应用于w。
So, this is apply pi of f to w.
因此，这是将f的pi应用于w。
And then do pi of f pi of f w.
然后做f w的pi。
And so on and so forth.
等等等等。
And that's what you do in order to construct the shortest path.
这就是您为了构造最短路径所做的事情。
People buy that?
人们买那个？
Right?
对？
And what I want to do here is apply pi b to w.
我想在这里将pi b应用于w。
And then, pi b of pi b to w.
然后，将pi b中的pi b转换为w。
And so on and so forth, till I get to t.
依此类推，直到我开始。
Right?
对？
And this one, till I get to s.
而这个，直到我得到。
Right?
对？
So, what I wrote here, s to w, t to w.
所以，我在这里写的是，从s到w，从t到w。
There's nothing incorrect about that.
没什么不对的。
What's important to understand is the application of the pi
重要的是要了解pi的应用
f and the pi b.
f和pi b。
Both, according to this, start with w,
因此，两者都以w开头，
which is this vertex that caused the termination to happen.
导致终止发生的顶点。
All right?
好吧？
So, people buy this?
那么，人们买这个吗？
Any other questions?
还有其他问题吗？
All right.
好吧。
Turns out this is not quite correct.
事实证明这不是很正确。
OK?
好？
This is not quite correct, right?
这不是很正确，对吧？
And not because of the pi b inversion that I had before,
并不是因为我之前的pi b反演，
right?
对？
So what have I said, so far?
那么到目前为止，我说了什么？
It makes perfect sense.
这是很合理的。
It says, I have a vertex that caused the termination.
它说，我有一个导致终止的顶点。
I'm going to call it w.
我将其称为w。
OK?
好？
And that vertex is on the intersection of these two
那个顶点在这两个的交点上
frontiers, OK?
边疆好不好
And I'm going to use that to construct the shortest
我将用它来构造最短的
path by constructing two sub paths,
通过构造两个子路径，
using the forward pointers and the backward pointers.
使用前向指针和后向指针。
All right?
好吧？
So all of that makes sense except,
所以所有这一切都有意义，除了，
it turns out, that w may not be on the shortest path.
事实证明，w可能不在最短路径上。
OK?
好？
And I'll show you an example where
我会给你举一个例子
w is not on the shortest path.
w不在最短路径上。
All right?
好吧？
So that's at a real subtle condition.
所以这是一个真正的微妙条件。
So we have to actually augment the termination condition.
因此，我们实际上必须增加终止条件。
Or, we have to do something more than the termination condition.
或者，除了终止条件，我们还需要做更多的事情。
So, I will tell you right away, the termination condition
所以，我马上告诉你终止条件
is correct.
是正确的。
OK?
好？
And so, the guy who got the cushion, deserved the cushion.
因此，得到靠垫的那个人应该得到靠垫。
OK?
好？
So the termination condition as correct.
因此终止条件正确。
You are going to run Dijkstra 's ultimate forward search
您将运行Dijkstra的终极搜索
and backward search.
和向后搜索。
And you're going to terminate when a particular vertex, call
当特定的顶点调用时，您将终止
it w, is going to get pulled out from both Qf and Qb.
它要从Qf和Qb中拉出来。
All right?
好吧？
What is incorrect here is the use of w
这里不正确的是使用w
to construct the shortest path.
构造最短的路径。
All right?
好吧？
It turns out, we have to do a little more work
事实证明，我们需要做更多的工作
to go find the shortest path, after we've terminated.
我们终止后去寻找最短的路径。
And w may not be on the shortest path.
w可能不在最短的路径上。
All right?
好吧？
Any ideas as to what we might do?
关于我们可能做什么的任何想法？
This is a bit of an unfair question,
这是一个不公平的问题，
but certainly worth a cushion.
但肯定值得缓冲。
How do you think we can fix this?
您认为我们如何解决这个问题？
If w is not on the shortest path,
如果w不在最短路径上，
what do you think would be on the shortest path?
您认为最短的路线是什么？
Is there a way of finding this vertex,
有没有找到这个顶点的方法，
so we can break this up?
这样我们可以分手吗？
We absolutely have to use both pi f and pi b.
我们绝对必须同时使用pi f和pi b。
There's no getting away from that
没有摆脱它的地方
because these two frontiers have just barely collided.
因为这两个领域刚刚相撞。
The instant they barely collided, we've stopped.
他们几乎没有发生碰撞的那一刻，我们就停了下来。
OK?
好？
So we can't use pi f all the way from s to t.
因此，我们不能从s到t一直使用pi f。
We can't use pi b all the way from t to s.
从t到s，我们不能一直使用pi b。
These frontiers have just barely collided.
这些边界刚刚相撞。
OK?
好？
So what happens if w is not on the shortest path?
那么，如果w不在最短路径上会发生什么呢？
And why is that the case?
为什么会这样呢？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: I just had a question.
听众：我只是有一个问题。
Are all the edge weights identical?
所有边缘权重都相同吗？
Or are they--
还是他们-
PROFESSOR: So, the edge weights don't change.
教授：因此，边缘权重不会改变。
There are no new edges.
没有新的优势。
The way you want to think about is
你想的方法是
that, you can traverse the edges backward.
您可以向后移动边缘。
And so, it's not like there are two edges here.
因此，这并不像这里有两个边缘。
Now, you could fake it, and have two edges
现在，您可以伪造它，并具有两个优势
with exactly the same weights over here.
此处的权重完全相同。
But are you saying there are edge weights in the graph,
但是您是说图中有边缘权重，
all identical across the edges?
所有相同的边缘？
Or are you asking about the forward search
还是您在询问正向搜索
versus the backward search?
与向后搜索？
AUDIENCE: That's what I was asking.
听众：那是我要的。
Is each edge weight the same in the graph.
图中每个边的权重是否相同？
PROFESSOR: No.
教授：不。
They're using Dijkstra.
他们正在使用Dijkstra。
The edge ways can be arbitrary.
边缘方式可以是任意的。
But they're non-negative.
但是它们不是负数。
OK?
好？
So that's the usual Dijkstra requirement.
这就是通常的Dijkstra要求。
They could be real numbers.
它们可以是实数。
They could be irrational numbers.
他们可能是不合理的数字。
They could be whatever.
他们可以是任何东西。
But they're all non-negative.
但是它们都是非负的。
All right?
好吧？
Now, in the backward search and the forward search-- just
现在，在向后搜索和向前搜索中，
to make that clear-- while I've drawn this particular edge,
为了明确起见-虽然我画了这个特殊的边缘，
that weight hasn't changed, OK?
体重没有改变，好吗？
That weight had better be the same.
那个重量最好是一样的。
OK?
好？
All right, so I'll show you an example.
好的，我给你看一个例子。
And we'll take an example, a fairly straightforward example,
我们将举一个例子，一个相当简单的例子，
it turns out.
事实证明。
It took a while to concoct this five node
花费了一些时间炮制这五个节点
example that shows the idea here.
在此处显示想法的示例。
But what we're going to do is, take a look at the termination
但是我们要做的是，看看终止
condition in a specific case, where
在特定情况下的条件
we're going to do this alternation of forward
我们将进行前向轮换
and backward search.
和向后搜索。
And we'll see, when it terminates,
我们会看到，当它终止时，
as to what the correct way is to construct the shortest path.
关于构造最短路径的正确方法是什么
All right?
好吧？
And, as I said before, the termination condition
而且，正如我之前说的，终止条件
is correct.
是正确的。
It's not like we stop too early.
并不是说我们停得太早。
When one of those nodes gets off from Qf and Qb,
当这些节点之一从Qf和Qb下车时，
you get to stop.
你停下来。
So that's my s, over here.
这就是我的，在这里。
And I have a fairly straightforward graph.
我有一个相当简单的图表。
I have 5, 5, 3, 3, 3.
我有5、5、3、3、3。
So we don't need a computer program
因此我们不需要计算机程序
to tell us that the shortest path from s to t
告诉我们从s到t的最短路径
is the path with three edges that goes on top, OK,
是具有三个边缘的路径，好，
which has a weight of 9.
权重为9。
All right.
好吧。
So this is a forward search.
所以这是向前搜索。
And I'm going to call all of these vertices names.
我将把所有这些顶点命名为“顶点”。
So I have u prime.
所以我有素。
t. et cetera.
t。等等。
OK?
好？
So, in the first step of the forward search,
因此，在正向搜索的第一步中，
I'm going to be able to set-- oh, I'm sorry.
我将能够进行设置-抱歉，对不起。
This one is a w.
这个是w。
I'm going to be able to set df w equals 5.
我将能够将df w设置为5。
And df u equals 3.
而df u等于3。
And, obviously, df of s equals 0.
显然，s的df等于0。
And I'm not going to bother writing the infinities.
而且我不会费心写无穷大。
It's just going to clutter up the board, all right?
这只会使董事会混乱，好吗？
So, stop me if you have questions on anything
所以，如果您有任何疑问，请阻止我
I'm writing here.
我在这里写。
So that's a forward search.
所以这是向前搜索。
Now, let's do the first step of backward search, right?
现在，让我们进行向后搜索的第一步，对吧？
Alternate, remember?
备用，还记得吗？
Alternate forward search, backward search,
交替向前搜索，向后搜索，
forward search, backward search.
向前搜索，向后搜索。
And I'm just going to write this out again,
我将再次写出来，
so bear with me, because I think it'd
所以忍受我，因为我认为
be clearer if you see this graph many times.
如果您多次看到此图表，请更清楚。
As opposed to my erasing what I've written.
与删除我写的内容相反。
So I've got an s, here.
所以我在这里有一个s。
t there.
在那里。
u.
你
u prime.
总理。
w.
w。
And I'm going to hash this vertex vertically
我将垂直哈希此顶点
because that's my backward search.
因为那是我的向后搜索。
And db of t equals 0.
t的db等于0。
OK?
好？
And I'm going to follow this backward, and this backward.
我将遵循此后退，以及此后退。
And my weights are the same.
我的体重是一样的。
It's the same graph.
这是同一张图。
So I'm going to have d of b u prime equals 3.
因此，我将使d的素数d等于3。
And db of w equals 5.
w的db等于5。
And I haven't seen u yet.
而且我还没有看到你。
I haven't seen s yet.
我还没看过。
And so, all I've done is mark these two.
因此，我所做的只是标记这两个。
All right?
好吧？
So far, so good?
到现在为止还挺好？
Again, stop me if you have questions.
同样，如果您有任何疑问，请阻止我。
We've got, obviously, a couple more steps to go here.
显然，我们还有几个步骤要去这里。
And let's keep going.
让我们继续前进。
So now we do a forward search again.
因此，现在我们再次进行前向搜索。
Yeah, that's fine.
是的，很好。
That's this hash that way, just to make sure.
这就是这种哈希，只是为了确保。
This is s, u, u prime, w, t.
这是s，u，u质数，w，t。
And what I have now is, I'm going
现在我要去的是
process this vertex in the forward search
在正向搜索中处理此顶点
because I have a choice in the forward search
因为我在向前搜索中有选择
to either pick w or w.
选择w或w。
This clearly has lower priority because df w equals 5.
显然，它的优先级较低，因为df w等于5。
And df of u equals 3.
u的df等于3。
So extract-min is obviously going to pick u.
因此，extract-min很显然会选择您。
And it's going to process this edge now, after extract-min.
在extract-min之后，它将立即处理此边缘。
And I'm going have df of u prime equals 6.
我要得到的素数df等于6。
OK?
好？
AUDIENCE: It's 3 over there.
听众：那边是3点。
PROFESSOR: Oh, it's 3 over there.
教授：哦，那边是3点。
Thanks.
谢谢。
Good.
好。
So, so far, so good?
那么，到目前为止，很好吗？
Yeah?
是啊
All right.
好吧。
So now, I go to the backward search.
所以现在，我去向后搜索。
And again, I have s, t, u, u prime, w.
再说一次，我有s，t，u，u素数w。
I'm going to go ahead and hash this.
我将继续对此进行哈希处理。
This has been hashed horizontally.
这已被水平散列。
The hash horizontally means that it's been removed from Qf.
水平散列表示已将其从Qf中删除。
The hash vertically means that it's been removed from Qb.
纵向上的哈希表示已将其从Qb中删除。
And so, when I look at this, and I do a backward search,
因此，当我查看此内容并进行向后搜索时，
I'm going to hash this.
我将对此进行哈希处理。
And I'm going to set db of u prime equals 3.
我将设置u的db等于3。
And I have db of w equals 5.
我的w的分贝等于5。
So, that I already had.
所以，我已经有了。
And so, when I have db of w equals 5 and db of u prime
所以，当我的w的分贝等于5而u的分贝
equals 3, then, obviously, I'm going
等于3，那么，显然，我要
to pick the one with the min priority.
选择优先级最低的那个
This corresponds to this one.
这与此对应。
And what it's going to do is, it's
它要做的是
going to go process that and set db of u equals 6.
进行处理，并将您的db设置为6。
All right?
好吧？
So what happened here simply was that I picked this vertex off
所以这里发生的只是我摘下了这个顶点
of Qb because that was the min priority.
Qb，因为这是最低优先级。
And all I did was relax this particular edge
我所做的就是放松这个特殊的优势
in the backward direction.
在向后的方向。
And said db u equals 6.
并说db u等于6。
All right?
好吧？
Almost there.
快好了。
Any questions so far?
到目前为止有什么问题吗？
Any bugs you noticed so far, in what I've written?
到目前为止，您在我写的文章中发现任何错误吗？
Yeah, back there, question.
是的，回到那里，问。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Good.
好。
So people agree with this.
因此人们对此表示赞同。
All right, one more.
好吧，再说一遍。
One more board to draw.
再画一个板。
And we'll be done.
我们会完成的。
We will have terminated.
我们将终止。
All right, so getting pretty close.
好吧，所以距离很近。
So I'm set up this way.
所以我是这样设置的。
Oh, shoot.
哦，开枪。
Sorry.
抱歉。
This is horizontal.
这是水平的。
So, now I'm looking at it, and I've taken care of these two.
因此，现在我正在研究它，并且已经处理了这两个问题。
And I'm talking about the forward search here.
我在这里谈论正向搜索。
So this is, again, the forward.
所以这又是前进的方向。
And that's the backward.
那就是落后。
And now I'm doing a forward again.
现在，我再次前进。
And my only choice, now, is to pick the w vertex off of Qf.
现在，我唯一的选择是从Qf中选择w顶点。
Right?
对？
Because df w equals 5.
因为df w等于5。
And this one has already been processed.
并且这个已经被处理了。
df of u equals 3.
u的df等于3。
But I've hashed that.
但是我已经将其散列了。
And so I've gone ahead and processed that vertex.
因此，我继续进行处理该顶点。
And this one, df of u prime equals 6.
这个素数的df等于6。
So, in Qf, I would be comparing u prime and w.
因此，在Qf中，我将比较u prime和w。
And I would take w, OK?
我会拿w，好吗？
People buy that?
人们买那个？
That's because, I guess you by the fact that 5 is less than 6.
这是因为，我猜您是5小于6。
I hope.
我希望。
So that's what happens in the step of forward search.
这就是正向搜索步骤中发生的情况。
And then you go ahead and process this.
然后继续进行处理。
You're going to set df of t to be 10.
您将把t的df设置为10。
OK?
好？
And now you're starting to see why
现在您开始明白为什么
there may be a bit of a problem with our shortest path
我们最短的路径可能会出现问题
computation, right?
计算吧？
Maybe.
也许。
All right?
好吧？
Everything good?
一切都很好？
All right.
好吧。
So what have I done here?
那我在这里做了什么？
I've removed w from Qf.
我已经从Qf中删除了w。
OK.
好。
I've removed w from Qf.
我已经从Qf中删除了w。
All right.
好吧。
Now, let's look at the last step here, of the backward search.
现在，让我们看一下向后搜索的最后一步。
s, t.
s，t。
And so, this was hashed.
因此，这是哈希值。
That was hashed.
那是散列的。
And, if I look at what I have here,
而且，如果我看看这里的东西，
I have db u prime equals 3.
我的分贝u等于3。
df u prime equals 6.
df u等于6。
This was df w equals 5.
这是dw w等于5。
db w equals 5.
db w等于5。
And so on and so forth.
等等等等。
Again, you compare w.
同样，您比较w。
And you see that db w equals 5.
您会看到db w等于5。
And df u prime equals 6.
df u素数等于6。
So therefore, you will pick w.
因此，您将选择w。
OK?
好？
You will pick w, and remove it from Qf.
您将选择w，并将其从Qf中删除。
So remove w from Qf.
因此，从Qf中删除w。
All right?
好吧？
And process it.
并处理它。
And what you end up with is df of s equals 10.
最终得到的是的df等于10。
OK?
好？
That's what you get because this is a 5.
这就是您得到的，因为这是5。
And that's a 5.
那是5。
OK?
好？
People see the problem here?
人们在这里看到问题了吗？
What's the problem?
有什么问题？
Someone articulate the problem.
有人明确指出了这个问题。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
I mean, so, what I have so far is, I've terminated.
我的意思是，到目前为止，我已经终止了。
But it looks like I end up with d of s.
但看起来我最终得到s的d。
If I look at it from a standpoint
如果我从一个角度来看
of the forward weight, I got a 10 for t.
向前重量的一半，我得到10吨。
I get db t equals 10.
我得到db t等于10。
If I look from a standpoint of the backward weight,
如果从后向重量的角度来看，
I get db s equals 10.
我得到db等于10。
OK?
好？
And we all know that the shortest path should be 9.
我们都知道最短路径应该是9。
OK.
好。
So what happened here?
那么这里发生了什么？
Well, we terminated according to this condition.
好吧，我们根据这种情况终止了。
We terminated when w was pulled off from Qf and Qb
当w从Qf和Qb断开时，我们终止了
because that was the short path, in some sense,
因为从某种意义上说，这是一条短路，
in terms of number of edges, right?
就边缘数量而言，对吗？
It was only of length 2.
它只有长度2。
And so, then the frontiers collide.
因此，边界发生了冲突。
This is a subtlety in the algorithm.
这是算法中的一个微妙之处。
The frontiers collide at some vertex,
边界在某个顶点发生碰撞，
regardless of the weights of the edges.
无论边缘的重量如何。
Because we are alternating the forward search
因为我们交替进行正向搜索
and the backward search, in effect,
实际上，向后搜索
the frontiers are going to collide on the shortest length
边界将在最短的长度上发生碰撞
path.
路径。
Right?
对？
That makes sense, right?
那是有道理的，对吧？
So this example is set up so the shortest length path is not
因此，此示例已设置，因此最短的路径不是
the shortest weight path.
最短的重量路径。
OK?
好？
So we can't take the w and use pi f to construct
所以我们不能使用w并使用pi f来构造
part of the path, and use pi b to construct
路径的一部分，并使用pi b进行构造
the other part of the path.
路径的另一部分。
And find the shortest weight path.
并找到最短的重量路径。
We would get something incorrect.
我们会得到不正确的东西。
Right?
对？
We would get a path of length 10, in this case,
我们将得到一个长度为10的路径，在这种情况下，
if we did that.
如果我们做到了。
So how do we fix it?
那么我们如何解决呢？
How do we fix it?
我们该如何解决？
One little termination condition doesn't change.
一个小的终止条件不会改变。
How do we fix it?
我们该如何解决？
Someone?
有人吗
Back there.
回到那里。
Or, actually, you.
或者，实际上是你。
AUDIENCE: Ordinate based on the weight.
听众：以体重为准。
PROFESSOR: Ordinate based on the weight.
教授：根据重量进行排序。
So exactly how would we do that?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
AUDIENCE: At each point you take the one
听众：在每一点上你都
that has the [INAUDIBLE].
有[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: But that's what we're doing now, right?
教授：但这就是我们现在正在做的，对吧？
So, are you changing the alternation
所以，您是否要更改交替
between the forward search and the backward search?
在向前搜索和向后搜索之间？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: You're saying that you're
教授：您是说您在
going to do more forward searches, as opposed
会进行更多的前向搜索，而不是
to backward searches?
向后搜索？
AUDIENCE: If the overall cost is lower.
听众：如果总体成本较低。
PROFESSOR: Overall cost is lower.
教授：总体成本较低。
You know, if you code it up, you get to keep this.
您知道，如果对它进行编码，就可以保留它。
If I want a slightly different, simpler
如果我想稍微不同一点，更简单
fix because I think what you're saying here--
解决，因为我认为您在这里说的是-
and I like the idea.
我喜欢这个主意
I actually do like the idea.
我实际上很喜欢这个主意。
You're saying you're going to not do strict alternation.
您是说您不会进行严格的轮换。
But you're going to do some sort of weighted alternation,
但是您将要进行某种加权交替，
from what I can tell, based on the weights.
我可以根据权重判断。
OK?
好？
And I think there's an algorithm there that's correct.
我认为这里有一个正确的算法。
OK?
好？
I probably won't be able to prove
我可能无法证明
that it's correct to myself in five minutes.
五分钟之内对我自己是正确的。
OK.
好。
Or 10 minutes.
或10分钟。
But let's talk about that offline.
但是，让我们离线讨论一下。
And see if there's a way.
看看是否有办法。
I'm a little worried that, if you
我有点担心，如果你
have positive rational numbers, and you've
有正有理数，而你已经
got root 2, square root of 2, and pi.
得到根2、2的平方根和pi。
And the transcendental number corresponding to these weights,
与这些权重相对应的超越数，
that this weighted alternation is
这个加权的交替是
going to be a bit hard to implement correctly.
正确实施会有些困难。
But it's a neat idea.
但这是一个好主意。
I would actually like a follow up on that.
我实际上希望对此进行跟进。
Something that's a little-- yeah, back there.
有点儿-是的，回到那儿。
AUDIENCE: Can you look at the neighbors of all the nodes that
听众：您能看一下所有节点的邻居吗？
are in your forward [INAUDIBLE], and see
在你的前进中[听不清]，
if any of their neighbors are in backwards [INAUDIBLE].
如果他们的任何邻居都倒向[听不清]。
And see if that's going to give you a shorter path than the one
看看这是否会让您走得更短
that you pulled out previously.
是你以前退出的
PROFESSOR: That's correct.
教授：是的。
That's almost exactly correct.
这几乎是完全正确的。
I won't bother throwing it over, but this is yours.
我不会把它扔过去，但这是你的。
You want to catch it?
你想抓住吗？
AUDIENCE: I already have one.
听众：我已经有一个。
PROFESSOR: You already have a cushion.
教授：您已经坐垫了。
All right.
好吧。
So how about I just throw it.
那我就扔吧。
And anybody who wants to catch it gets it.
任何想要抓住它的人都可以得到它。
How's that?
怎么样？
Whoa.
哇
All right.
好吧。
I didn't hit anybody.
我没打人
Anybody who wants it, who doesn't have a cushion.
任何想要它的人，没有缓冲。
Right.
对。
We've got all these cushions in my office, and Eric's office.
我们办公室和Eric的办公室都有这些垫子。
We've got to do something about them.
我们必须对它们做一些事情。
They're actually not that great.
他们实际上不是那么好。
You know, it's bit of an issue, I understand.
我知道，这是个问题。
You know, we've got to do Frisbees next time,
你知道，我们下次必须做飞盘，
or something.
或者其他的东西。
I can see why you're not enthusiastic about this.
我明白了您为什么不对此感兴趣。
Right?
对？
OK.
好。
All right, so the answer was, in fact, correct.
好吧，答案实际上是正确的。
And let me write it up over here.
让我在这里写下来。
So we had to do a little more work.
因此，我们不得不做更多的工作。
We terminate properly.
我们正确终止。
We do the strict alternation.
我们进行严格的变更。
But we have to do a little bit more work.
但是，我们需要做更多的工作。
OK.
好。
And the work we have to do is summarized very neatly
我们要做的工作总结得很整齐
by saying, we want to find an x, which is maybe
就是说，我们想找到一个x，也许
different from w, possibly, that has
与w不同，可能有
minimum value of d of x plus db x.
x加上db x的d的最小值。
All right?
好吧？
So we have to actually look.
因此，我们必须实际看一下。
And this x is going to be neighboring.
这个x将是相邻的。
But we don't really need to specify that.
但是我们真的不需要指定它。
What we say is, you're going to have to look at Qf and Qb.
我们的意思是，您将不得不考虑Qf和Qb。
And it's possible that w is the one that
w可能是
has minimum df w plus db w.
具有最小dw和db w。
But, clearly, that wasn't the case in this example.
但是，显然，在此示例中并非如此。
So, in this example, w caused the termination.
因此，在此示例中，w导致了终止。
But now we need to scan.
但是现在我们需要扫描。
And there's only two other vertices
而且只有两个顶点
that are interesting here, which are u and u prime.
在这里有趣的是你和你素数。
And either of those will fit the bill
这些都适合
because we see that df of u plus db of u equals 3 plus 6
因为我们看到u的d加上u的db等于3加6
equals 9.
等于9。
And df of u prime plus db of u prime equals-- I'm sorry,
u素数的df和u素数的db等于-对不起，
I should have out db here.
我应该在这里有分贝。
db of u prime would be 6 plus 3 equals 9.
u prime的db是6加3等于9。
Right?
对？
So both of these are less than 10.
所以这两个都小于10。
And so we had to pick one of these as our x.
因此，我们必须选择其中一个作为x。
OK.
好。
And if you pick one of these as our x, then, at that point,
如果您选择其中一个作为x，那么在那时，
we don't do w here.
我们在这里不做。
We do x.
我们做x。
OK?
好？
Let me write it as x.
让我将其写为x。
It looks like a cross here.
这里看起来像个十字架。
So that's what happens.
就是这样。
So this small little tweak.
所以这个小小的调整。
Do the alternation.
进行轮换。
Do the termination.
执行终止。
Once you do the termination, go look
终止后，请继续查看
and see if you can minimize the shortest path
看看是否可以最小化最短路径
length by finding an appropriate x.
通过找到适当的x来确定长度。
Which has the minimum sum of the forward and the backward
其中前向和后向的总和最小
priorities.
优先事项。
And then, you're in business.
然后，您正在做生意。
And then, everything works.
然后，一切正常。
OK?
好？
All right.
好吧。
Great.
大。
So, so much for bi-directional search.
因此，双向搜索就这么多。
Let me talk a little bit about heuristics
让我谈谈启发式
that people use to modify the graph so things run faster
人们用来修改图形，以便更快地运行
in practice.
在实践中。
So, in particular, you can think about the goal directed search,
因此，尤其是您可以考虑目标定向搜索，
or a star, if you're taking 6034.
或星星，如果您要使用6034。
And there's some commonality between what
两者之间有一些共同点
I'm going to talk about here, and that material.
我将在这里讨论该材料。
The basic idea is that we're going
基本思想是我们要
to modify the edge weights in such a way
以这种方式修改边缘权重
that you go downhill toward the shortest path.
沿着最短的路走下坡路。
And so, the priorities are modified heuristically.
因此，优先级将通过启发式修改。
So things run a little bit quicker.
这样事情就快一点了。
You're trying to prune the search here.
您正在尝试修剪此处的搜索。
So we're going to modify edge weights.
因此，我们将修改边缘权重。
And we have to be careful when we do this, obviously.
显然，我们必须谨慎行事。
We don't want to do things that are incorrect.
我们不想做不正确的事情。
But the way we want to modify the edge weights
但是我们想要修改边缘权重的方法
is by having some sort of potential function
是通过具有某种潜在功能
that corresponds to lambda.
对应于lambda。
And, if the edge is between u and v,
而且，如果边在u和v之间，
then we have an equation given a lambda that says,
那么我们有一个给出了lambda的方程式，
the new w, w bar, is w u, v minus lambda u plus lambda
新的w，w bar是wu，v减去lambda u加lambda
v. OK?
v。好吗？
Now, we have to be a little careful here, with respect
现在，我们必须在此谨慎一点
to the choice of lambda.
选择lambda。
But the basic idea, in terms of lambda,
但是基本概念，就lambda而言，
is that, suppose you have something like this,
是的，假设您有这样的事情，
where you have a source vertex, s.
在其中具有源顶点的位置。
And you're again trying to do a single source,
您再次尝试做一个单一来源，
single target going to t.
单一目标去t。
And let's say I have an edge of weight 5 going out
假设我有5的优势
and an edge of a 5 going out this way.
和这样的优势5的边缘。
Is there a way that you can guess
有没有办法可以猜到
that this is the edge that is more
这是更多的优势
likely to be on your shortest path?
可能是您最短的路？
As opposed to this other edge?
相对于另一优势？
Essentially increase the potential
从根本上增加潜力
of this node, all right?
这个节点的，好吗？
So this node here may be the node t2.
因此，此节点可能是节点t2。
And this node may be the node t1.
并且该节点可以是节点t1。
You want to increase the potential of node t2,
您想增加节点t2的潜力，
such that, you're actually trying
这样，您实际上正在尝试
to go uphill when you go this way.
这样走上坡路。
And this goes downhill.
这很艰难。
And that has the appropriate modifications
并进行了适当的修改
on the edge weights, such that the Dijkstra algorithm is
在边缘权重上，例如Dijkstra算法是
steered towards going downhill.
转向下坡。
And going down this path.
然后走这条路。
And it terminates a little bit quicker.
而且终止更快。
Right?
对？
It doesn't change as asymptotic complexity.
它不会随着渐进复杂性而改变。
It just makes things run, in practice, a little bit faster.
实际上，它只是使事情运行得更快。
If you choose the right potentials.
如果您选择合适的潜力。
Right?
对？
Feels like magic.
感觉就像魔术。
How do you know how to increase the potential?
您怎么知道如何增加潜力？
What would you increase the potential for?
您会增加什么潜力？
What nodes do you want to make uphill?
您要爬坡哪些节点？
What nodes do you want to make downhill?
您想下坡哪些节点？
So there's a bunch of questions.
所以有很多问题。
I'm not going to get into a lot of details.
我不会涉及很多细节。
But I will tell you a couple of things.
但是我会告诉你一些事情。
I'm going to give you, really quickly, a simple example
我将很快给你一个简单的例子
that is both correct, in terms of the actual shortest path you
就您实际的最短路径而言，这都是正确的
will get is the correct one.
会得到正确的答案。
And a particular mechanism off modifying
还有一种特殊的修改机制
the potentials that uses landmarks.
利用地标的潜力。
Right.
对。
So the way we are going to do this
所以我们要做的方式
is by saying that any path wp is going
就是说任何路径wp都会走
to get modified based on its destination and source.
根据其目的地和来源进行修改。
So the only way that we can use the potential method
因此，我们可以使用潜在方法的唯一方法
is by ensuring that all of the shortest
通过确保所有最短的
paths between any pair of vertices, we're
任意一对顶点之间的路径
only concerned about single source, single target here.
这里只关注单一来源，单一目标。
But, in general, it's a good thing
但是，总的来说，这是一件好事
to not change any of the shortest paths.
不改变任何最短的路径。
So what used to be a shortest path
那曾经是最短的道路
should stay the shortest path.
应该走最短的路。
And the way you do that is by having
而你要做的就是
a potential function that, if you have an arbitrary
一个潜在的功能，如果您具有任意性
path, essentially-- and this is a path from s to t.
本质上是路径-这是从s到t的路径。
That you subtract out something based
你减去一些基于
on a function of the vertex.
在顶点的函数上。
In this case, you have s.
在这种情况下，您有。
And, in this case, you have t.
并且，在这种情况下，您有t。
So the nice thing is that, any path from s to t
所以很高兴的是，从s到t的任何路径
is going to get shifted by the same amount, corresponding
将要移动相同的数量，对应
to this additional term here.
这个附加条款。
So what that means is that the final shortest
所以这意味着最后的最短
path that you discover will be the correct shortest path.
您发现的路径将是正确的最短路径。
You just may, hopefully, discover it faster.
希望您可以更快地发现它。
All right?
好吧？
So that's the correctness check.
这就是正确性检查。
And I'll put this in the notes.
我将其放在笔记中。
And maybe the TAs can cover it in the section.
也许TA可以在本节中介绍它。
But one way of getting this potential function
但是获得这种潜在功能的一种方法
is to use what's called a landmark.
使用所谓的地标。
And so the basic idea is that you have a landmark, l,
因此，基本思路是，您具有地标性，
which is a vertex belonging to v.
这是属于v的顶点。
And we're going to pre-compute delta of u comma l.
我们将预先计算u逗号的增量。
So, for any input vertex, you want
因此，对于任何输入顶点，
to find the shortest path to this landmark.
找到通往这个地标的最短路径。
So it's like, change the source, but the destination
就像更改源，但更改目标
stays the same.
保持不变。
And the potential lambda t u is defined
并定义了潜在的lambda tu
as delta of u, l minus delta of t, l.
作为u，l的增量减去t，l的增量。
OK?
好？
So you have the source, s.
因此，您有来源。
You have a destination, t.
您有目的地，t。
And now you have a landmark, l.
现在您有了一个里程碑。
I'm going to pre-compute delta u,l for all u belonging to v.
我将为属于v的所有u预先计算delta u，l。
And I'm also going to pre-compute, for a given t,
对于给定的t，我还要进行预计算
delta t, l.
三角洲湖
So that's just a single t.
因此，这仅是一个t。
So that's just one computation.
因此，这只是一种计算。
This one is much more computation.
这是更多的计算。
And, if I use this potential, you can show that it's correct,
而且，如果我利用这一潜力，您可以证明它是正确的，
using the triangle inequality.
使用三角形不等式。
And this is not a heuristic.
这不是启发式的。
With the correct choice of landmark,
正确选择地标，
Dijkstra, empirically, will run faster.
根据经验，Dijkstra将运行得更快。
So, if you know for sure that you
因此，如果您确定知道自己
need to go through middle America to get from Cal Tech
需要经历中美洲才能从Cal Tech获得
to Boston-- and there's one particular landmark
到波士顿-有一个特别的地标
you want to go through-- Texas or something.
您想经历-德州之类的
And you pick Austin, Texas, then you can do this computation.
然后选择德克萨斯州的奥斯丁，然后就可以进行此计算了。
And maybe Dijkstra runs 2x faster, 20% faster.
也许Dijkstra的运行速度快了2倍，快了20％。
All right?
好吧？
I'll put the argument about correctness, and the specifics
我会提出关于正确性和具体性的论点
of these things, in the notes.
这些东西，在笔记中。
And you can take a look at it offline.
您可以离线查看它。